One of the needs we may have when running queries
is to find records where certain values are empty,
whether by design or by accident. Take, for
example, this query that has some header
information for sales orders. There is a rumor
that some orders may be missing a SalesPersonID.
I will add a WHERE clause to this query that
looks for empty values in the SalesPersonID
field to find those orders. There are two keys
to understand. First, the keyword for empty is
NULL. Secondly, we do not want to use equals NULL
because technically, we would look for the word
NULL. We do not want that. We are looking to see
if a field is null, and that is what we will type
here. I will execute this, and it turns out over
60000 orders do not have a SalesPersonID. Maybe
there is a huge data entry problem, or this is
by design, like a cash sale or something similar.
To compare orders with no SalesPersonID
with orders that do have one,
I will change the criteria from NULL
to NOT NULL and execute this again,
and we have about 60000 orders with a
SalesPersonID. Therefore, this was probably
by design. The takeaway here is that the NULL
keyword will help us find those empty values.